<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-20T20:52:47+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Expedient</title><subtitle>Expedient Demo Site for Forestry.io</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Private vs. Public Cloud: What’s the Difference?</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/private-vs-public-cloud-whats-difference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Private vs. Public Cloud: What’s the Difference?" /><published>2014-06-05T14:29:09+00:00</published><updated>2014-06-05T14:29:09+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/private-vs-public-cloud-whats-difference</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/private-vs-public-cloud-whats-difference/">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been researching cloud computing, you’re probably well aware of the private vs. public cloud debate. Before you decide which end of the debate you side with, it’s important to know the difference between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;private-cloud&quot;&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/private-cloud/&quot; title=&quot;Private&quot;&gt;A private cloud hosting solution&lt;/a&gt;, also known as an internal or enterprise cloud, resides on company’s intranet or hosted data center where all of your data is protected behind a firewall. This can be a great option for companies who already have expensive data centers because they can use their current infrastructure. However, the main drawback people see with a private cloud is that all management, maintenance and updating of data centers is the responsibility of the company. Over time, it’s expected that your servers will need to be replaced, which can get very expensive. On the other hand, private clouds offer an increased level of security and they share very few, if any, resources with other organizations. See how food additive manufacturer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ticgums.com/&quot;&gt;TIC Gums&lt;/a&gt; realized the best of both worlds with Expedient’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/managed-services/disaster-recovery/#onsite&quot;&gt;On-Site Private Cloud with DRaaS&lt;/a&gt; Solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;public-cloud&quot;&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main differentiator between public and private clouds is that you aren’t responsible for any of the management of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/public-cloud/&quot; title=&quot;Public&quot;&gt;public cloud hosting solution&lt;/a&gt;. Your data is stored in the provider’s data center and the provider is responsible for the management and maintenance of the data center. This type of cloud environment is appealing to many companies because it reduces lead times in testing and deploying new products. However, the drawback is that many companies feel security could be lacking with a public cloud. Even though you don’t control the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/five-strategies-to-mitigate-cloud-risk/&quot; title=&quot;Three Security Criteria to Consider When Selecting Your Cloud Hosting Provider&quot;&gt;security of a public cloud,&lt;/a&gt; all of your data remains separate from others and security breaches of public clouds are rare. So which is right for you? Ultimately, it all boils down to control. A large company may choose a private cloud, while a smaller business might choose a public cloud. &lt;strong&gt;Think ‘Public Cloud’ just means AWS or Azure? Think again. &lt;/strong&gt;In a recent third-party performance analysis, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient’s Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; outperformed comparable offerings from AWS, Azure and Rackspace in nearly every category tested. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/2019-cloud-spectator-report/&quot;&gt;Download the report from Cloud Spectator to learn more.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;As Vice President of Product Strategy, John White is the lead executive at Expedient responsible for the company’s product and technology vision. In addition to leading Expedient’s product strategy function, John also serves as the lead technology evangelist for the company, works closely with the sales team on closing complex/high brand deals, and acts as Expedient’s primary interface with existing technology partners. Connect with John &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:John.White@expedient.com&quot;&gt;via email&lt;/a&gt; and follow him on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johna_white&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Cloud Computing" /><category term="cloud computing" /><category term="private cloud computing" /><category term="public cloud computing" /><category term="cloud security" /><category term="private cloud" /><category term="public cloud" /><category term="John White" /><summary type="html">If you’ve been researching cloud computing, you’re probably well aware of the private vs. public cloud debate. Before you decide which end of the debate you side with, it’s important to know the difference between the two.</summary></entry></feed>