<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-12T13:21:55-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Expedient</title><subtitle>Expedient Demo Site for Forestry.io</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Expedient Sessions at VMworld 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-08-11-expedient-sessions-at-vmworld-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expedient Sessions at VMworld 2019" /><published>2019-08-11T10:45:58-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-11T10:45:58-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/expedient-sessions-at-vmworld-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-08-11-expedient-sessions-at-vmworld-2019/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vmworld.com/en/us/index.html&quot;&gt;VMworld&lt;/a&gt; is back in the Bay and the Expedient team is busier than ever! This year we have 5 sessions, booth duties with awesome Expedient demos focusing on our Enterprise Cloud product, multi-cloud management product, Push Button DR (DRaaS), and Backup as a Service, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecube.net/vmworld-2019&quot;&gt;a Cube interview&lt;/a&gt; with our partner Cohesity, and an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.actualtechmedia.com/event-schedule/?leads%5B%5D=400&amp;amp;topic%5B%5D=3#EventSchedule&quot;&gt;EcoCast with ActualTech Media&lt;/a&gt;. Of course we have parties as well, more on that in another blog post, today we are going to focus on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=expedient&quot;&gt;Expedient sessions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;expedient-hyper-growth-cloud-provider-powered-by-vmware-vcloud-director-hbi2806bu--john-white&quot;&gt;Expedient: Hyper-growth cloud provider powered by VMware vCloud Director [&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=HBI2806BU&quot;&gt;HBI2806BU&lt;/a&gt;] – John White&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At VMworld 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/expedient-cloud-evolution-a-vision-5-years-in-the-making/&quot;&gt;we debuted Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; via a session following the keynote &lt;a href=&quot;https://videos.vmworld.com/global/2018?q=john%2520white&quot;&gt;with a live demo&lt;/a&gt;. For VMworld 2019, we are going to share the success we have had on the platform and highlight why we think a VMware based cloud is the ideal solution for most cloud destined workloads. Attend this session to get an inside scoop as I share some of our secret sauce on why/how VMware recognized us as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/expedient-named-vmwares-americas-cloud-partner-of-the-year/&quot;&gt;2018 Americas Cloud Partner of the Year&lt;/a&gt; and our fastest growing product ever – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;architecting-vmware-cloud-roundtable-hbi2615pu--john-white&quot;&gt;Architecting VMware Cloud Roundtable [&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=HBI2615PU&quot;&gt;HBI2615PU&lt;/a&gt;] – John White&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really looking forward to this session as the ability to ask questions of your peers and gain new perspective is at the heart of a successful VMworld. In this session, we will do just that for a whole hour! Come ask questions to David Grimes of Navisite, John Dwyer, Martin Hosken, and Daniel Paluszek of VMware, and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vBrownbag sessions are a great opportunity to talk about any type of tech and provides the opportunity for anyone in the community talk about what they are passionate about. This year Expedient has three sessions from Brent Meadows, Mike Morris, and yours truly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;building-a-kubernetes-cluster-in-12-minutes-with-vcloud-director--cse-vmtn5054u--brent-meadows&quot;&gt;Building a Kubernetes Cluster in 12 Minutes with vCloud Director &amp;amp; CSE [&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=VMTN5054U&quot;&gt;VMTN5054U&lt;/a&gt;] – Brent Meadows&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost every developer is asking for a Kubernetes environment for development work or even production. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/deploy-kubernetes-clusters-alongside-virtual-machines-with-expedient-enterprise-cloud/&quot;&gt;VMware has built a product offering&lt;/a&gt; to suit each need with their Container Service Extension (CSE) for vCloud Director, and then their work with the Heptio and Pivotal teams. Brent will show you how easy it is to get a CSE cluster up in a vCloud Director environment to provide turnkey Kubernetes with no extra licensing cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;getting-started-with-infrastructure-as-code-using-terraform-and-vcloud-director-vmtn5036u--mike-morris&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Infrastructure as Code using Terraform and vCloud Director [&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=VMTN5036U&quot;&gt;VMTN5036U&lt;/a&gt;] – Mike Morris&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/infrastructure-as-code-four-ways-to-automate-vmware-cloud-management/&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as code&lt;/a&gt; is all the rage right now as we look to automate as much as humanly possible. In this TechTalk, Mike will show how easy it is to use Terraform to instantiate VM’s using the powerful vCloud Director APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;building-a-cloud-native-app-vmtn5005u--john-white&quot;&gt;Building a Cloud Native App [&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.vmworld.com/widget/vmware/vmworld19us/us19catalog?search=VMTN5005U&quot;&gt;VMTN5005U&lt;/a&gt;] – John White&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I am going to walk through my journey of learning how to build my first Cloud Native Application on AWS. The end result was a pretty killer scalable application having some fun with my colleague, Sam Sarnicke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, we will be busy the week of VMworld and we hope to connect with as many of the attendees as possible. I hope to see you in a session or at the booth. Follow Expedient on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/_expedient/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Expedient&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for up-to-date info on sessions and parties. See you in San Fran!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Chief Innovation Officer, John White is the lead executive at Expedient responsible for the company’s product and technology vision. In addition to leading Expedient’s product strategy function, John also serves as the lead technology evangelist for the company, works closely with the sales team on closing complex/high brand deals, and acts as Expedient’s primary interface with existing technology partners. Follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johna_white&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">VMworld is back in the Bay and the Expedient team is busier than ever! This year we have 5 sessions, booth duties with awesome Expedient demos focusing on our Enterprise Cloud product, multi-cloud management product, Push Button DR (DRaaS), and Backup as a Service, a Cube interview with our partner Cohesity, and an EcoCast with ActualTech Media. Of course we have parties as well, more on that in another blog post, today we are going to focus on the Expedient sessions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social--vmworld2019.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyperscale or Enterprise - Which Cloud is Best for Your Business?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-which-cloud-is-best-for-your-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyperscale or Enterprise - Which Cloud is Best for Your Business?" /><published>2019-07-18T16:36:56-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T16:36:56-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-which-cloud-is-best-for-your-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-which-cloud-is-best-for-your-business/">&lt;p&gt;The cloud provider landscape is complex and constantly evolving. To meet the performance demands of legacy compute workloads and to control cloud costs, many businesses are opting for hosted enterprise clouds instead of the mainstream hyperscale options provided by AWS, Azure and Google Cloud. During &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=owgkJHsMcRY&amp;amp;#t=3m10s&quot;&gt;our recent webinar&lt;/a&gt;, I was joined by &lt;a href=&quot;https://451research.com/analyst-team/analyst/Carl+Brooks&quot;&gt;Carl Brooks&lt;/a&gt;, Analyst with 451 research, to discuss several key topics shaping enterprise cloud transformation, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Cloud adoption trends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The drivers of workload placement across various cloud venues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The common challenges enterprises face during cloud transformation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The differences between hyperscale clouds and enterprise clouds, and the impact these characteristics have on application performance and cloud cost control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/2019-cloud-spectator-report/&quot;&gt;recent cloud benchmark report&lt;/a&gt; that compared Expedient Enterprise Cloud with clouds from AWS, Azure and Rackspace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;watch-the-full-replay-of-the-webinar-now&quot;&gt;Watch the full replay of the webinar now:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-responsive w-7/12&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;663&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/owgkJHsMcRY?start=190&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Cloud Computing" /><category term="private cloud" /><category term="public cloud" /><category term="hybrid cloud" /><category term="digital transformation" /><summary type="html">The cloud provider landscape is complex and constantly evolving. To meet the performance demands of legacy compute workloads and to control cloud costs, many businesses are opting for hosted enterprise clouds instead of the mainstream hyperscale options provided by AWS, Azure and Google Cloud. During our recent webinar, I was joined by Carl Brooks, Analyst with 451 research, to discuss several key topics shaping enterprise cloud transformation, including:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/451Webinar-Cover-Slide_july2019.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">VMware CloudSpot Podcast with Expedient’s John White</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-18-vmware-cloudspot-podcast-with-expedients-john-white/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VMware CloudSpot Podcast with Expedient's John White" /><published>2019-07-18T10:45:58-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T10:45:58-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/vmware-cloudspot-podcast-with-expedients-john-white</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-18-vmware-cloudspot-podcast-with-expedients-john-white/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/30EuoDS&quot;&gt;Listen to John White&lt;/a&gt;, Expedient’s Chief Innovation Officer, and Guy Bartram, Director of Product Marketing at VMware, discuss Expedient’s evolution as a VMware Cloud Provider Partner on VMware’s CloudSpot Podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information on the podcast is available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2XYXPPg&quot;&gt;VMware’s blog here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><category term="Cloud Computing" /><category term="VMware" /><category term="Expedient Enterprise Cloud" /><summary type="html">Listen to John White, Expedient’s Chief Innovation Officer, and Guy Bartram, Director of Product Marketing at VMware, discuss Expedient’s evolution as a VMware Cloud Provider Partner on VMware’s CloudSpot Podcast.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/3568_VMware_Podcast_LinkedIn_Ep5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Repurposing IT - How cloud-based VMware infrastructure enables better strategic focus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-12-repurposing-it-how-cloud-based-vmware-infrastructure-enables-better-strategic-focus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repurposing IT - How cloud-based VMware infrastructure enables better strategic focus" /><published>2019-07-12T16:22:07-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T16:22:07-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/repurposing-it-how-cloud-based-vmware-infrastructure-enables-better-strategic-focus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-12-repurposing-it-how-cloud-based-vmware-infrastructure-enables-better-strategic-focus/">&lt;p&gt;How strategic is your IT team? Ask two questions to get a sense of your strategic value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask the employees in your organization &lt;strong&gt;whether they feel like Information Technology makes the organization run more effectively.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As an IT professional, ask yourself &lt;strong&gt;whether your IT team helps your organization get the most out of its critical business applications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer to either of these questions isn’t yes, your IT team may have a strategic focus problem. I’ll define strategic focus as the ability to find, prioritize and deliver business applications that drive better customer service, new lines of business, higher revenue, and lower costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-chronic-problem--it-infrastructure&quot;&gt;The Chronic Problem – IT infrastructure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether its located in-house or at a colocated data center facility, selecting, managing, maintaining, and repairing IT infrastructure still accounts for a huge portion of the IT team’s available work hours.  Add in the choices for cloud-based servers, storage and software, and an IT team can quickly become overwhelmed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/how-are-you-addressing-the-10-complexities-of-your-multi-cloud-environment/&quot;&gt;the complexity inherent&lt;/a&gt; in supporting multiple clouds and on-premises systems.  This infrastructure-focused work leaves little to no time for the IT team to focus on helping the business run more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-solution---optimize-your-cloud-stack-based-on-business-requirements&quot;&gt;The Solution - Optimize Your Cloud Stack Based on Business Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are successful IT teams doing to improve their organizations and help their internal customers get the most out of their applications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choosing an optimized combination of SaaS, enterprise cloud platforms, hyperscale cloud, and on-premises equipment based on business requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimizing infrastructure-related workloads using enterprise VMware-based cloud for legacy applications, hyperscale cloud for new development, and SaaS applications when functionality and cost make sense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many organizations, the key to reducing infrastructure is the intelligent use of enterprise cloud. Enterprise cloud is VMware-based cloud infrastructure with these characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance –&lt;/strong&gt; Most organizations expect their applications to run faster on newer IT platforms. The best enterprise cloud providers provide higher memory, disk and network performance for better application experiences.  Hyperscale clouds and SaaS don’t measure up to the best enterprise cloud performance levels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comfort –&lt;/strong&gt; Your critical business applications are comfortable running on VMware-based infrastructure, and your Systems Administrators are comfortable using the VMware management plane.  Hyperscale cloud often includes a learning curve and new skillsets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economics –&lt;/strong&gt; Ultimately, the cost of IT must be in alignment with the value it brings to the business. The best enterprise cloud providers offer predictable spending and cost changes that reflect changes in the business.  Accurate cost evaluations should include estimated reduction in FTE hours, licensing and hardware maintenance costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service level –&lt;/strong&gt; How much downtime can your organization tolerate? Hyperscale cloud provider’s 99.95% uptime means more than four hours of downtime per year is acceptable.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Enterprise cloud providers such as Expedient&lt;/a&gt; offer 100% uptime with service credits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API –&lt;/strong&gt; As more companies automate IT functions, application programming interfaces (APIs) become critical for enabling optimized IT management processes. The best enterprise cloud providers deliver APIs to enable automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-is-still-more-to-do-the-it-team-still-must-repurpose-the-freed-up-time-to&quot;&gt;There is still more to do.  The IT team still must repurpose the freed-up time to:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work closely with the organization to evaluate, implement, support and change critical business applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead the organization to better long-term technology planning and usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skeptical?  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/resources/video-prodigo-solutions-reduces-customer-onboarding-time-with-expedients-cloud-and-managed-services/&quot;&gt;See how Prodigo Solutions&lt;/a&gt; reduced their tactical IT infrastructure workload and refocused on new applications and better business outcomes.  Or contact me to discuss your organization’s specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doug Theis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the Director of Market Strategy in Expedient’s Indianapolis market focused on engaging with and improving the regional IT community through planning, sponsoring and attending community events, facilitating IT-focused continuing education opportunities, and sharing strategies, tactics, and research to help IT professionals stay abreast of best practices and industry trends. Connect with Doug at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:doug.theis@expedient.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;doug.theis@expedient.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dougtheis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Doug Theis</name></author><category term="Cloud Computing" /><category term="Infrastructure as a service" /><category term="hyperscale cloud" /><category term="digital transformation" /><category term="IT Leadership" /><summary type="html">How strategic is your IT team? Ask two questions to get a sense of your strategic value:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social--repurposing_it.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Infrastructure as Code: Four Ways to Automate VMware Cloud Management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-10-infrastructure-as-code-four-ways-to-automate-vmware-cloud-management/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infrastructure as Code: Four Ways to Automate VMware Cloud Management" /><published>2019-07-10T14:33:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-10T14:33:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/infrastructure-as-code-four-ways-to-automate-vmware-cloud-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-07-10-infrastructure-as-code-four-ways-to-automate-vmware-cloud-management/">&lt;p&gt;For years, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/on-premises-it-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;IT infrastructure provisioning was a manual process&lt;/a&gt;.  This made sense when deploying a new server meant placing a purchase order, waiting for gear to arrive, racking the new gear, and then finally applying a bespoke configuration to support a new workload.  However, now that most workloads are moving to the cloud, new VMs can be provisioned in seconds meaning that manual provisioning adds hours or days to the process, which creates additional friction with every new deployment.  Even if the additional time lag is not a factor for your business, every minute an engineer spends following a SOP to deploy a new machine is a minute they aren’t spending working to improve your environment and make it faster, improve its stability, or provide additional capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse than the time lost to provisioning toil is the potential for inconsistency introduced by relying on humans to apply configurations to every server by hand.  People make mistakes, and even if you have a robust QA process on every new machine (more valuable engineer time lost!), inevitably, some things will slip through the cracks.  Over time, these small deviations add up and eventually make it difficult or impossible to confidently describe the current state of your environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/expedient-cloud-evolution-a-vision-5-years-in-the-making/&quot;&gt;Adopting an infrastructure as code approach&lt;/a&gt; enables the automation of rote provisioning operations, which will free up your engineers to work on improving your environment.  At the same time, you will be removing a major source of potential inconsistency or misconfiguration caused by human error, improving both the stability and security of your infrastructure.  Finally, having your infrastructure defined as code and managed in an SCM like Github means that you can always be certain of the current state of your environment and have total insight into all changes made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within VMware’s Cloud environment, there are various ways to implement an Infrastructure as Code approach.  For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (EEC) platform – which is based on VMware’s vCloud Director provisioning and management platform – offers a complete REST API to streamline integration with your existing automation tooling.  Continue reading for more detail on this ‘Infrastructure as Code’ approach and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directly-using-the-rest-api&quot;&gt;Directly using the REST API&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The REST API can be interacted with directly from any programming language with HTTP support or tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getpostman.com/&quot;&gt;Postman&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://insomnia.rest/&quot;&gt;Insomnia&lt;/a&gt;.  There are some pitfalls with this approach, but we created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://apidocs.expedient.cloud/?version=latest&quot;&gt;Postman collection with documentation&lt;/a&gt; to assist in understanding the various API endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is approach is highly flexible, supporting development in any language or automation tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good for extending existing tooling with new features to complete your automation workflows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete coverage – All capabilities exposed by vCD can be accessed via the REST API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In general, this approach is less user friendly than other available options.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More time-consuming than pre-made tooling or libraries when performing common operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shell-scripting-with-vcd-cli&quot;&gt;Shell scripting with vCD-cli&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vmware.github.io/vcd-cli/&quot;&gt;Vcd-cli&lt;/a&gt; is a Python-based command-line utility that can be used to perform the most common administration tasks within vCD. Just remember that in order to access the vCloud command line interface (CLI), an up-to-date python installation is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On mac OS and Linux, installation is simple using &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpython.com/what-is-pip/&quot;&gt;Python’s PIP package manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The vCD-cli leverages common BASH scripting skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is useful for performing one-off tasks from the command line such as VM deployments, hardware adjustments, and network connection changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Somewhat more complicated install on Windows platforms as that you will need &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/downloads/&quot;&gt;to install the Visual C++ build tools&lt;/a&gt; in addition to Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BASH is not necessarily ideal for complex automation tasks when compared with other languages or configuration management tooling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-client-librariessdks&quot;&gt;Using client libraries/SDKs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are client libraries available for both &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vmware/pyvcloud&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vmware/go-vcloud-director&quot;&gt;the Golang SDK for vCD&lt;/a&gt; that can be used to perform the vast majority of administration operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This approach is generally more user-friendly and facilitates faster development than the plain REST API.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capable of integrating with other software/processes as long as either Python or Go are supported&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Still retains good flexibility and covers most operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confined to two specific programming languages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some features exposed by the API are not yet accessible in the libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-modern-automation-tooling&quot;&gt;Using modern automation tooling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vCD is well supported by modern automation tooling such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt;.  These modules allow you to easily automate common operations like server deployment, network creation, and firewall rule adjustments using declarative configuration files. &lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This approach leverages existing expertise with configuration management tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows for declarative configuration
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Easier for non-programmers to read and modify&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Facilitates much faster time to market due with the ability to create simpler automation workflows&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Automation playbooks can be given to auditors in place of SOP documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requires learning new tooling if expertise does not already exist within the organization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Often means increased support costs if not purely using the OSS projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Somewhat limited in scope compared with the number of operations that are exposed via the API and included in the SDKs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, there are several different ways to automate the deployment, configuration and management of IT infrastructure within vCD. As I mentioned previously, an Infrastructure as Code approach to IT infrastructure management definitely has its benefits. Just make sure you choose the approach that is best for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Garuccio is a Product Strategy Engineer at Expedient focused on researching new software and hardware to find ways to productize this technology into new solutions for Expedient clients. As a ‘full stack’ engineer, Mike works with all layers of infrastructure architecture - from the hypervisor all the way up to front-end applications. Mike has played a leading role in the deployment and implementation of Expedient’s next-generation cloud platform, Expedient Enterprise Cloud. His professional interests include automation, containers, Kubernetes, CI/CD, and developer experience optimization. Follow Mike on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgaruccio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mike Garuccio</name></author><category term="Cloud Computing" /><category term="DevOps" /><summary type="html">For years, IT infrastructure provisioning was a manual process.  This made sense when deploying a new server meant placing a purchase order, waiting for gear to arrive, racking the new gear, and then finally applying a bespoke configuration to support a new workload.  However, now that most workloads are moving to the cloud, new VMs can be provisioned in seconds meaning that manual provisioning adds hours or days to the process, which creates additional friction with every new deployment.  Even if the additional time lag is not a factor for your business, every minute an engineer spends following a SOP to deploy a new machine is a minute they aren’t spending working to improve your environment and make it faster, improve its stability, or provide additional capabilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social--infa-as-code%20(1).png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Key Takeaways from Gartner’s 2019 Security and Risk Management Summit – The Business Case for Organizational Resilience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-28-key-takeaways-from-gartners-2019-security-and-risk-management-summit-the-business-case-for-organizational-resilience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Key Takeaways from Gartner's 2019 Security and Risk Management Summit – The Business Case for Organizational Resilience" /><published>2019-06-28T15:20:08-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-28T15:20:08-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/key-takeaways-from-gartners-2019-security-and-risk-management-summit-the-business-case-for-organizational-resilience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-28-key-takeaways-from-gartners-2019-security-and-risk-management-summit-the-business-case-for-organizational-resilience/">&lt;p&gt;More than 3,500 IT risk and security professionals congregated outside of Washington, D.C., recently to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/conferences/na/security-risk-management-us&quot;&gt;2019 Gartner Security and Risk Management Summit&lt;/a&gt; to gain the latest insights on evolving security trends and the ever-changing threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was among the team from Expedient who were there to meet with vendors, partners, clients, and analysts. Throughout the week, several topic areas were comprehensively covered with respect to some of today’s top priorities for security and risk in digital business. These were key areas where I focused my engagement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choosing Cybersecurity Standards and Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt; – continuously improving an effective posture that meets the broadest needs of organization that rely on Expedient services to achieve business resilience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Compliance Challenges&lt;/strong&gt; – designing, implementing, and integrating risk management systems based upon the government and industry mandates that apply to a variety of client vertical industries requiring business resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-principles-of-organizational-resilience&quot;&gt;The Principles of Organizational Resilience&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have for the past three years, I attended sessions on the topic of &lt;strong&gt;organizational resilience&lt;/strong&gt;, which Gartner defines as a set of techniques that allow people, processes, and information systems to adapt to changing patterns. This approach enables the ability to adjust operations in the face of changing business conditions. Integrating the principles of Organizational Resilience into day-to-day operations will provide a platform for our clients to more closely manage risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interest in this topic is related to Expedient’s position as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/managed-services/disaster-recovery/&quot;&gt;disaster recovery as a service (DRaaS)&lt;/a&gt; solution provider. Through DRaaS and managed security services, Expedient plays a role in the organizational resilience of its clients by providing co-managed capabilities that protect data and reduce the likelihood of pervasive threats from impacting day-to-day business operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-agile-is-your-business&quot;&gt;How Agile is Your Business?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building upon the posture of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/is-your-organization-continuousnext/&quot;&gt;ContinuousNEXT&lt;/a&gt; that I first heard about at Gartner’s 2018 Symposium, Organizational Resilience confronts changes in technology, competition, and business in order to possess the capability to adapt as the pace of change quickens. To embody this approach, business leaders are challenged to introduce new practices, develop new capabilities, and create new ways to succeed. Partnering with a service provider is one way accelerate implementation of this approach to managing risk and enhancing security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were several thought leaders and inspirational guest speakers at the conference, including &lt;strong&gt;Michael Chertoff&lt;/strong&gt; (former Secretary of Homeland Security), &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Lencioni&lt;/strong&gt; (author of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Five-Dysfunctions-Team-Leadership-Fable/dp/0787960756&quot;&gt;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team&lt;/a&gt;”), &lt;strong&gt;Nicole Malachowski&lt;/strong&gt; (retired U.S. Air Force Colonel and first female Thunderbird Pilot and Combat Veteran), and others. Each speaker offered a different perspective on the theme of change that connects back to the concepts of &lt;strong&gt;ContinuousNEXT&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/the-evolution-of-disaster-recovery-gaining-it-resilience/&quot;&gt;Organizational Resilience&lt;/a&gt; that are needed to adapt to digital business operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Senior Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, Jonathan Rosenson is responsible for overseeing organizational functions that drive growth at Expedient. Jon additionally acts as an external spokesperson conveying the Expedient story.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rosenson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow him&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Rosenson</name></author><category term="Security and Compliance" /><category term="Disaster Recovery" /><category term="managed services" /><category term="risk management" /><summary type="html">More than 3,500 IT risk and security professionals congregated outside of Washington, D.C., recently to attend the 2019 Gartner Security and Risk Management Summit to gain the latest insights on evolving security trends and the ever-changing threat landscape.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social--Gartner_Summit.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Differences Between Backups and Disaster Recovery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-27-the-differences-between-backups-and-disaster-recovery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Differences Between Backups and Disaster Recovery" /><published>2019-06-27T09:55:50-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-27T09:55:50-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/the-differences-between-backups-and-disaster-recovery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-27-the-differences-between-backups-and-disaster-recovery/">&lt;p&gt;Modern IT departments need to be able to protect their mission-critical data and quickly respond in the event of a problem in their environment.   This capability hinges on maintaining a strategy for both backups and disaster recovery.  These two capabilities &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/what-are-the-differences-between-backups-and-disaster-recovery/&quot;&gt;are often conflated with each other&lt;/a&gt; but this blog post will explore the differences between the two and explain the situations they are needed for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;backups&quot;&gt;Backups&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backups have been around almost as long as computers themselves and revolve around making point-in-time copies of all data on a given system.  A good backup solution should be capable of restoring anything from a single file to an entire system to a recently known-good state.  These backups are crucial in several situations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A developer accidentally drops a table from a production database and it needs to be restored.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A user accidentally deletes a file from a shared drive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A single server fails due to a bad software update and must be restored to the state it was in prior to the change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A server is impacted by ransomware or other malware renders it unusable.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h5 id=&quot;infrastructure-integrations&quot;&gt;Infrastructure Integrations&lt;/h5&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re running workloads on physical servers, a local hypervisor (vCenter) or in the cloud, your backup solution should work with the underlying infrastructure to leverage capabilities like snapshots, which will enable performant backups and rapid restores of entire systems.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h5 id=&quot;application-compatibility&quot;&gt;Application Compatibility&lt;/h5&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Applications, particularly databases, often have their own requirements for performing successful backups and restores. Before settling on a backup solution, you should ensure that it is compatible with your existing applications and be aware of any special procedures that are required to perform successful backup that can be restored.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h5 id=&quot;rporto&quot;&gt;RPO/RTO&lt;/h5&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If any of the issues listed above occurs, how long of an outage is acceptable (defined by Recovery Time Objective (RTO)), and how much data loss is acceptable (defined by Recovery Point Objective (RPO)).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;disaster-recovery&quot;&gt;Disaster Recovery&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 years ago, the disaster recovery plans of most organizations involved moving a set of their backup tapes off-site at the end of every week and calling it a day.  That is fine as long as the business is OK with the idea of potentially losing a week’s worth of work and being offline until a new data center is set up and all of the systems are restored.  Of course, most businesses in 2019 simply can’t survive that sort of operational disruption, so new solutions must be devised to deliver the desired level of IT availability. &lt;strong&gt;Here are a few scenarios that your disaster recovery solution should be able to handle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The obvious – some disaster that physically damages/destroys the data center where your workloads exist, such as:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Earthquake&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Water leak in some office that exists above the data center, causing a flood&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A full network outage in your primary data center, so while the systems may still be running they are not accessible to your users.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A long-term power outage at your office (assuming your infrastructure is in an office data center rather than a colocation facility).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing with the issues above while maintaining the availability the business demands obviously requires a solution that goes beyond backups and includes a number of additional requirements, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A “hot site”&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Basically, this entails a disparate location other than your data center where your workloads can be rapidly brought online and made available to your users.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous replication&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To meet the aggressive RPO’s modern businesses demand in the event of a disaster, data needs to be continuously replicated to the hot-site so that data loss is minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This data replication feature is also incredibly useful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/cloud-migration-strategies-how-to-choose-the-right-one/&quot;&gt;for migrating workloads&lt;/a&gt; from one environment to another with minimal downtime.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After a fail-over takes place how do your users connect to the new environment? For smaller organizations this can be as simple as desktop engineers working with users to point their local machines to the new location, but for larger organizations, this needs to happen automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The considerations for a DR platform are similar but slightly different than those for a backup solution. They include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Integrations&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A DR solution needs to be natively compatible with both the infrastructure you are protecting and the environment you plan to recover to.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;IF you are planning to use a recovery site that is using a different hypervisor than your primary site (e.g. failing over to a hyperscale cloud or from a physical server into a VM) it is also important that your DR solution have a way of re-configuring the machine operating system to have the correct drivers and other software packages for the new environment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPO/RTO&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Many modern DR solutions enable near-real-time RPOs, however this is heavily dependent on your network link to the recovery site and your data change rate.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Due to differences in how cloud providers work internally, different backup solutions offer a range of RTO’s on different platforms. It is important to look at the expected RTO for the source site/recovery site/DR software combination you plan to use and ensure that the RTO for this combination meets the requirements of your business.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency requirements&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unlike traditional backups, DR solutions are generally not aware of underlying applications like databases. This means that additional care must be taken to ensure that data is consistent across servers in the event of an unexpected failover.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some DR solutions incorporate the idea of a “&lt;strong&gt;consistency group&lt;/strong&gt;” which ensures that a group of servers are always being restored to the exact same point in time to avoid inconsistency issues after a restore.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After a failover is completed, a full DR solution should take steps to ensure that users are able to reach their applications quickly and without direct intervention from IT staff.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The traditional way of handling this is to reconfigure DNS entries to point to the new site, however this method of failover can take a long time to propagate to all users, particularly if they are globally distributed or if long TTL’s exist on the entries themselves. Whatever the case, make sure to account for this additional time in your RTO calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;An alternate way of dealing with this problem is to fail over the entire networking stack with the compute resources and announce the same IP addresses from the new location. This requires a deep integration with the infrastructure of both the source and destination sites. By automating and orchestrating network failover, Expedient’s Push Button DR solution enables this failover approach, which enables real-time RPOs and RTOs measured in minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these DR capabilities are wonderful, it’s important to remember that as of right now most DR solutions are optimized for the recovery of VMs but are lacking in important backup features like the ability to rapidly restore a single file deleted by a user or bringing back a database table that was mistakenly dropped. Since your business will most likely require a combination of DR and backup functionality, a hybrid solution that supports both is typically recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help translating business requirements into a cohesive business continuity strategy that addresses both backups and disaster recovery? Expedient Solution Architects are adept at creating custom IT resilience solutions to match the specific needs of your business. Feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mike.garuccio@expedient.com&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; and I can put you in touch with an Expedient SA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Garuccio is a Product Strategy Engineer at Expedient focused on researching new software and hardware to find ways to productize this technology into new solutions for Expedient clients. As a ‘full stack’ engineer, Mike works with all layers of infrastructure architecture - from the hypervisor all the way up to front-end applications. Mike has played a leading role in the deployment and implementation of Expedient’s next-generation cloud platform, Expedient Enterprise Cloud. His professional interests include automation, containers, Kubernetes, CI/CD, and developer experience optimization. Follow Mike on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgaruccio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mike Garuccio</name></author><category term="Disaster Recovery" /><category term="managed services" /><summary type="html">Modern IT departments need to be able to protect their mission-critical data and quickly respond in the event of a problem in their environment.   This capability hinges on maintaining a strategy for both backups and disaster recovery.  These two capabilities are often conflated with each other but this blog post will explore the differences between the two and explain the situations they are needed for.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Garuccio_Blog--Backups-vs-DR_1.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyperscale or Enterprise Cloud? Let Your Applications Decide – Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyperscale or Enterprise Cloud? Let Your Applications Decide – Part 2" /><published>2019-06-18T11:33:35-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T11:33:35-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-2/">&lt;p&gt;This is the second installment of a two-part blog post on the difference between “smart” and “dumb” applications. Part 2 covers the characteristics of “dumb applications” that are best suited to run on “smart hardware.” To learn more about “smart applications” (aka cloud native applications) running on “dumb hardware,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-i/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dumb-applications-on-smart-hardware&quot;&gt;Dumb Applications on Smart Hardware&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumb applications&lt;/strong&gt; are traditional applications that typically run on Windows, Linux, and VMware infrastructure. There is little to no redundancy built in to the application code, hence “dumb applications.”  If the application needs to be highly reliable, the underlying computer hardware and operating system must be smart and resilient enough to handle hardware failures, network connection problems, and malware attacks, hence the term &lt;strong&gt;smart hardware&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most line of business applications like manufacturing ERPs, Electronic Medical Records, and industry-specific software still fall in to the category of dumb applications.  These applications were often developed before the advent of cloud computing and are still most applications running in on-premises, colocated data centers, and hosted Windows and Linux environments. The best fit for dumb applications on smart hardware is usually a &lt;strong&gt;hardware-redundant enterprise cloud&lt;/strong&gt; such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient’s Enterprise Cloud platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;enterprise-cloud-considerations&quot;&gt;Enterprise Cloud Considerations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When evaluating if an enterprise cloud is a good fit for a “dumb” application, make sure to consider the service by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Familiarity&lt;/strong&gt; – Does the enterprise cloud your considering use hypervisors, operating systems and tooling that are industry standard and familiar to your IT staff or your IT service providers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt; – Is the underlying hardware/software architecture fast enough to match or exceed the existing software implementation, or to meet your users’ needs?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economics&lt;/strong&gt; - Is the cost of using the enterprise cloud predictable? Does it show appropriate return on investment when the hardware, software licensing, data protection and reduction in IT staff labor is evaluated?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automation Capability&lt;/strong&gt; – Does the enterprise cloud have an API that allows your IT team to automate and control the compute environment programmatically?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service level agreements&lt;/strong&gt; – Does the enterprise cloud’s SLA match up with your organization’s expected recovery times and recovery points?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt; – How flexible will your network be with an enterprise cloud provider? Can you connect to an existing wide area network?  Can the enterprise cloud provider include connectivity in to the offering?  Does the enterprise cloud provider offer faster, more cost-conscious connections to multiple clouds if you need them?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial stability&lt;/strong&gt; – How long has the enterprise cloud provider delivered services? Does the provider innovate and improve their cloud regularly?  What is the debt load of the provider?  Who is the enterprise cloud provider’s first consideration:  stockholders, private equity, leadership or clients?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you know?&lt;/strong&gt; In a recent independent cloud analysis performed by Cloud Spectator LLC, the Expedient Enterprise Cloud platform largely outperformed comparable instances from AWS, Azure and Rackspace. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/2019-cloud-spectator-report/&quot;&gt;Download your free copy&lt;/a&gt; of the benchmark report to see the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doug Theis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the Director of Market Strategy in Expedient’s Indianapolis market focused on engaging with and improving the regional IT community through planning, sponsoring and attending community events, facilitating IT-focused continuing education opportunities, and sharing strategies, tactics, and research to help IT professionals stay abreast of best practices and industry trends. Connect with Doug at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:doug.theis@expedient.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;doug.theis@expedient.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dougtheis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Doug Theis</name></author><category term="private cloud" /><category term="hybrid cloud" /><category term="Multi-cloud" /><category term="hyperscale cloud" /><category term="VMware" /><category term="Expedient Enterprise Cloud" /><summary type="html">This is the second installment of a two-part blog post on the difference between “smart” and “dumb” applications. Part 2 covers the characteristics of “dumb applications” that are best suited to run on “smart hardware.” To learn more about “smart applications” (aka cloud native applications) running on “dumb hardware,” read Part 1.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social-Let-Your-Applications-Decide.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyperscale or Enterprise Cloud? Let Your Applications Decide – Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyperscale or Enterprise Cloud? Let Your Applications Decide – Part I" /><published>2019-06-18T11:31:53-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T11:31:53-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-18-hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-i/">&lt;p&gt;While many think buying cloud services is as easy as choosing between AWS or Azure, educated buyers explore all the options – both hyperscale and enterprise clouds - and choose the environment that will maximize application performance while optimizing cloud spend. Often, this best-of-breed approach &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/how-are-you-addressing-the-10-complexities-of-your-multi-cloud-environment/&quot;&gt;leads to complex multi-cloud and hybrid IT environments&lt;/a&gt; that consist of hyperscale clouds, private hosted clouds, on-premises and colocated infrastructure. So, what’s the key to multi-cloud success? You guessed it – choosing the right IT infrastructure for each specific use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a &lt;strong&gt;Best Execution Venue (BEV)&lt;/strong&gt; approach to workload placement starts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/should-your-organizations-applications-influence-which-cloud-platforms-you-use/&quot;&gt;with analyzing your applications&lt;/a&gt; to determine which cloud(s) would work best for each application. In the first section of this two-part article, we will explore the types of applications best suited for the hyperscale cloud and review what factors you should consider when choosing a hyperscale cloud provider. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-2/&quot;&gt;In the second part of this article&lt;/a&gt;, I will consider applications that typically work best in enterprise cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;smart-applications-on-dumb-hardware&quot;&gt;Smart Applications on Dumb Hardware&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Expedient, we commonly refer to applications that work best in the hyperscale cloud as “smart” applications running on “dumb” hardware. &lt;strong&gt;Smart applications&lt;/strong&gt; are newer applications developed with specific hyperscale cloud infrastructure in mind. These applications are smart because they are written to leverage specific hyperscale cloud features to protect the application from hardware failures, network problems and malware attacks.  The underlying hardware of the hyperscale clouds are built using tens of thousands of simple servers, often in an oversubscription model, hence the term &lt;strong&gt;dumb hardware&lt;/strong&gt;.  The dumb hardware has no capability to protect the application.  The smart application running on the dumb hardware handles high availability and resiliency, thus the best fit for smart applications on dumb hardware is typically a hyperscale cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hyperscale-cloud-considerations&quot;&gt;Hyperscale Cloud Considerations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to running virtual machines in the hyperscale cloud, there isn’t a whole lot of difference between the compute performance and per-instance pricing of the major hyperscale providers – AWS, Azure and Google Cloud Platform (GCP). For this reason, it makes sense that organizations gravitate toward the hyperscale provider that aligns best with their existing environment. For instance, organizations that already use Microsoft products will favor Azure as it will provide a better experience and cause fewer headaches for IT operations. Early on, AWS favored the open source development community, but now supports Windows development environments as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of the global hyperscalers, differentiation really starts to occur further up the stack where specific use cases and purpose-built infrastructure dictate which provider is optimal in certain situations. As an example, if you’re doing machine learning with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org/&quot;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt;, then GCP is a better fit since it offers specialized hardware to run those workloads faster and at a lower cost. However, if you’re doing event-driven serverless development, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&quot;&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt; is probably a better fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of specific cloud use cases like the two described above, you’ll want to consider various factors when evaluating hyperscale cloud services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographic availability&lt;/strong&gt; – One of the major selling points of the cloud is the ability to move workloads close to your users/customers, so it’s worth considering where your users are located and whether any of the hyperscale clouds have regions nearby that offer the services you plan to leverage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skillset&lt;/strong&gt; – Each of the hyperscale clouds offer a massive array of services and adoption will be much easier if your developers are already familiar with the particular set of services you plan to use to build your application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economics&lt;/strong&gt; – Depending on a workload’s requirements there may be large differences in pricing between different hyperscale clouds. As this pricing changes frequently, a &lt;strong&gt;cloud management console&lt;/strong&gt; can be a huge help in evaluating this on a per-workload basis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulations&lt;/strong&gt; – If you are in a regulated industry, it’s important to keep in mind that different cloud providers have different regulatory certifications, the lack of which may make them unsuitable for your application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Services&lt;/strong&gt; – The hyperscale clouds all have a range of managed services for things like databases and object stores… make sure to find out whether your developers plan to leverage any of these services.  If they do, it’s worth evaluating the differences between the hyperscale offerings on a few different points related to managed services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing&lt;/strong&gt; – This tends to be fairly competitive between the providers but, in some cases, they will use different models so it’s worth investigating the differences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability&lt;/strong&gt; – SLAs for managed database services tend to be different than those for compute instances so make sure to double check the SLA and ensure that it’s sufficient for your planned use case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling&lt;/strong&gt; – the various hyperscalers offer different ways to scale performance on their managed services, it is important to ensure that the service you select can scale to meet your needs affordably.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application architecture&lt;/strong&gt; – Different clouds encourage different ways of designing applications (although they tend to offer support for all models) and aligning your choice of provider to the way you plan to build your application can help avoid headaches down the line.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique offerings&lt;/strong&gt; – perhaps the most important factor that would lead you to choose one cloud over the other is unique offerings from a particular vendor as I previously illustrated with the TensorFlow and AWS Lambda examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/hyperscale-or-enterprise-cloud-let-your-applications-decide-part-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read the second part of this post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;to learn about the best type of cloud for “dumb applications” that require “smart hardware.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doug Theis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the Director of Market Strategy in Expedient’s Indianapolis market focused on engaging with and improving the regional IT community through planning, sponsoring and attending community events, facilitating IT-focused continuing education opportunities, and sharing strategies, tactics, and research to help IT professionals stay abreast of best practices and industry trends. Connect with Doug at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:doug.theis@expedient.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;doug.theis@expedient.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dougtheis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Doug Theis</name></author><category term="Infrastructure as a service" /><category term="public cloud" /><category term="hybrid cloud" /><category term="Multi-cloud" /><category term="hyperscale cloud" /><summary type="html">While many think buying cloud services is as easy as choosing between AWS or Azure, educated buyers explore all the options – both hyperscale and enterprise clouds - and choose the environment that will maximize application performance while optimizing cloud spend. Often, this best-of-breed approach leads to complex multi-cloud and hybrid IT environments that consist of hyperscale clouds, private hosted clouds, on-premises and colocated infrastructure. So, what’s the key to multi-cloud success? You guessed it – choosing the right IT infrastructure for each specific use case.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social-Let-Your-Applications-Decide.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Four Ways to Deploy Kubernetes on VMware</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-11-four-ways-to-deploy-kubernetes-on-vmware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four Ways to Deploy Kubernetes on VMware" /><published>2019-06-11T15:25:43-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-11T15:25:43-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/four-ways-to-deploy-kubernetes-on-vmware</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledgebase/blog/2019-06-11-four-ways-to-deploy-kubernetes-on-vmware/">&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes (k8s) is quickly becoming the de facto standard for container orchestration because it provides an effective framework to operate applications built using microservices architecture. Also known as application “containerization,” this approach enables development teams to be more agile, employ continuous delivery practices, and ultimately bring new business applications to market faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;k8s streamlines the management of containerized applications at scale.&lt;/strong&gt; Because of k8s, migrating production workloads from VMs to containers makes practical sense from a business perspective in many situations. However, using k8s for container orchestration will not be second nature for your application engineers. It requires learning several new skills, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declarative config (yaml)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service discovery and publishing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse Proxys/Ingress controllers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New monitoring methodologies, like&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreos/prometheus-operator&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prometheus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as you will learn, multiple different approaches can be taken to solve the same problem in k8s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;load-balancing&quot;&gt;Load Balancing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, there are multiple different ingress controllers you can use for load balancing such as NGINX, HAProxy, Envoy, and Traefik. To learn about each method, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubedex.com/ingress/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;logging&quot;&gt;Logging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting, viewing, managing and analyzing Kubernetes logs are crucial to the successful operation of your containerized application. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/elasticsearch-kubernetes&quot;&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datadoghq.com/log-management/&quot;&gt;Datadog&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vmware.com/products/vrealize-log-insight.html&quot;&gt;vRealize LogInsight&lt;/a&gt; are all useful tools in this area. A shameless, yet related product plug – Expedient offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/managed-services/compliance-security/unified-log-management/&quot;&gt;managed Log Insight service&lt;/a&gt; to make it easy for clients use it for BI purposes. Check it out when you have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deploying-kubernetes&quot;&gt;Deploying Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even deploying a k8s cluster is a relatively complex task as k8s is actually several components (kubelet, api server, proxy, dns server, etc) that work together and must be deployed across multiple nodes and configured to communicate with each other. There are several tools available to simplify this process depending on your needs – such as Kubeadm, Kubespray, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rancher.com/what-is-rancher/how-is-rancher-different/&quot;&gt;Rancher&lt;/a&gt; – and they each work best in specific scenarios. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altoros.com/blog/a-multitude-of-kubernetes-deployment-tools-kubespray-kops-and-kubeadm/&quot;&gt;This blog from Altoros&lt;/a&gt; provides some great context on Kubeadm and Kubespray. More on Rancher later…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;application-monitoring&quot;&gt;Application Monitoring&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that your application is fulfilling its intended purpose and staying within budget, keeping tabs on application performance and resource utilization after deployment is a must. Prometheus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.netdata.cloud/&quot;&gt;netdata&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sensu.io/solutions/container-monitoring&quot;&gt;Sensu&lt;/a&gt; are examples of monitoring tools with native k8s support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;distributions&quot;&gt;Distributions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Linux, the base k8s offering is augmented by various vendors and open-source projects. It’s possible to run ‘upstream’ k8s by deploying your master cluster &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/setup/independent/create-cluster-kubeadm/&quot;&gt;with kubeadm&lt;/a&gt; or a tool that relies on it. There are a number of other k8s distributions available from various vendors as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deploying-kubernetes-on-vmware--four-approaches&quot;&gt;Deploying Kubernetes on VMware – Four Approaches&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Kubernetes intro in the rear view, we can now talk about the fun stuff. Over the last year, Expedient’s Product Strategy and Information Systems teams have collaborated to deploy several containerized applications on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/infrastructure-as-a-service/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (EEC) platform, which is based on vCloud Director v9.5. As you know from my k8s intro above, there are several different ways to achieve similar results when deploying containerized applications on k8s. However, there are advantages and disadvantages to each approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual creation and management with kubeadm&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploy servers as you normally would and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/setup/independent/create-cluster-kubeadm/&quot;&gt;use kubeadm to bootstrap a kubernetes cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pure upstream Kubernetes, guaranteeing compatibility with any k8s workload and immediate availability of new versions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fewest new tools to learn&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allows customization of effectively any cluster feature&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provides a very bare-bones installation
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No GUI&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;No network overlay (this is easy to apply but still an extra step)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All lifecycle control is manual&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nodes need to be set up separately from the running of the kubeadm command, requiring either multiple steps or custom automation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ansible-based deployment with kubespray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploy servers manually and use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubespray&quot;&gt;ansible playbooks provided by the kubespray project&lt;/a&gt; to bootstrap and manage the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Based on kubeadm so k8s is fully upstream with quick availability of new versions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leverages existing ansible skills and infrastructure (if present)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provides options for deploying additional features like the network overlay&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provides basic lifecycle control automation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cluster still highly customizable&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Difficult to use if ansible is a new tool for the team&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nodes still need to be set up manually
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This is partially alleviated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.ansible.com/ansible-tower/latest/html/userguide/workflows.html&quot;&gt;by using Tower workflows&lt;/a&gt; to both deploy nodes and bootstrap clusters but still requires setup&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Use the Container Service Extension (CSE) for vCD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vmware.github.io/container-service-extension/CLUSTER_ADMIN.html#example&quot;&gt;Use the CSE extension of vcd-cli to deploy clusters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bootstraps both nodes and cluster so new cluster deployment can happen from a single CLI command&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allows creation and deletion of worker nodes with a single command&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploys a working network overlay&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Based on kubeadm so Kubernetes is fully upstream&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Relatively slow version updates compared with other options&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Minimal lifecycle management capability (worker node creation/deletion only)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kubeadm base means cluster is fairly bare-bones&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/blog/deploy-kubernetes-clusters-alongside-virtual-machines-with-expedient-enterprise-cloud/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; from John White, Expedient’s Chief Innovation Officer, for more on CSE for vCD.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Rancher&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploy an instance of &lt;a href=&quot;https://rancher.com/products/rancher/&quot;&gt;Rancher’s open source cluster management tool&lt;/a&gt; and use that for cluster creation/management&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deploys a more complete platform:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;RBAC (Role-based access control)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Easily enabled monitoring and logging&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Helm configured to make app deployment easier&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Full lifecycle management of nodes (cluster k8s version can be updated with a few clicks in web UI)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Complete GUI for monitoring and managing the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Currently still requires manually creating nodes and adding them to the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Additional tool to manage (Rancher itself)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Uses a fork of Kubernetes called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rancher/rke&quot;&gt;Rancher Kubernetes engine&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Still certified compatible but potential for incompatibility is still higher than upstream&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Updates tend to be slightly behind the upstream (typically by a month or two)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are many ways to get k8s up and running in a VMware-based cloud like EEC. If you would like more information on the approaches described above or k8s in general, feel free to email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mike.garuccio@expedient.com&quot;&gt;mike.garuccio@expedient.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Garuccio is a Product Strategy Engineer at Expedient focused on researching new software and hardware to find ways to productize this technology into new solutions for Expedient clients. As a ‘full stack’ engineer, Mike works with all layers of infrastructure architecture - from the hypervisor all the way up to front-end applications. Mike has played a leading role in the deployment and implementation of Expedient’s next-generation cloud platform, Expedient Enterprise Cloud. His professional interests include automation, containers, Kubernetes, CI/CD, and developer experience optimization. Follow Mike on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgaruccio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mike Garuccio</name></author><category term="containers" /><category term="digital transformation" /><category term="VMware" /><category term="Kubernetes" /><category term="DevOps" /><summary type="html">Kubernetes (k8s) is quickly becoming the de facto standard for container orchestration because it provides an effective framework to operate applications built using microservices architecture. Also known as application “containerization,” this approach enables development teams to be more agile, employ continuous delivery practices, and ultimately bring new business applications to market faster.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/EXP-Social-Four-Ways-to-Deploy-K8s-on-VMware.jpg" /></entry></feed>